What would life be like without music?
没有音乐的人生会是什么样子？
Songs and tunes fill our lives, affecting our emotions, bringing back memories and sometimes making us dance.
歌曲和旋律使我们生活更加充实，影响着我们的情绪，唤醒回忆，有时还会让我们翩翩起舞。
There is a song for everyone and for every occasion, but it seems that it’s sad music that moves us most.
每个人、每个场合都有对应的歌曲，但似乎最能打动我们的，是悲伤的音乐。
Sad music certainly does its job in making us depressed, emotional, and causing us to sob – it’s something we might listen to after a break-up, for example.
悲伤的音乐确实能起到让我们情绪低落、心生感触、甚至潸然泪下的作用——比如，分手后我们可能就会听这类音乐。
And a recent study has shown why some people are hooked on sad music.
最近一项研究揭示了有些人沉迷悲伤音乐的原因。
Professor David Huron from Ohio State University conducted the research and looked at the difference between people who love to listen to sad music and those who can’t stand it.
俄亥俄州立大学的大卫·休伦教授开展了这项研究，探究了热爱悲伤音乐与无法忍受悲伤音乐的人群之间的差异。
He told the BBC radio programme The Why Factor that it comes down to a natural hormone called prolactin. He says: “as you might have guessed from the name, it's associated with ‘lactation’ from breast-feeding.
他在接受BBC广播节目《原因何在》（The Why Factor）采访时表示，这归根结底与一种名为催乳素（prolactin）的天然激素有关。
When people cry, they also release prolactin.
他说：“从名字你可能就能猜到，它与母乳喂养中的‘泌乳’有关。
And, there are circumstances in which prolactin seems to have this comforting effect.”
人们哭泣时也会释放催乳素，而且在某些情况下，催乳素似乎能产生这种安慰效果。”
It seems that people who like sad music are maybe getting too much prolactin, or more than is normal, and when they hear sad, downbeat music, it gives them a good feeling.
喜欢悲伤音乐的人，体内的催乳素可能过多或超出正常水平，当他们听到悲伤、低沉的音乐时，会产生愉悦感。
But if prolactin isn’t released, or there isn’t enough of it, some people find the sad sounds don’t help to cheer them up.
但如果催乳素没有被释放，或者含量不足，有些人就会觉得悲伤的音乐无法让他们振作起来。
Previous research by Durham University has also suggested that listening to sad music can trigger pain and sadness; but it can also provide comfort and even enjoyment.
杜伦大学此前的一项研究也表明，听悲伤的音乐可能会引发痛苦和悲伤情绪，但同时也能带来安慰，甚至愉悦感。
A high number of people they surveyed were cheered up by listening to supposedly sad songs.
他们调查发现，很多人听了本应悲伤的歌曲后反而心情变好。
Though the feeling may not be exactly the same as happiness, it may be the ability to cope with the sadness that gives the feeling of comfort.
这种感觉或许与幸福感并不完全相同，但可能正是这种应对悲伤的能力，让人产生了舒适感。
So, reacting to sad music on the radio may have nothing to do with the melancholic sound of a string quartet or a singer who’s got the blues, but rather a natural chemical reaction taking place in our bodies.
因此，我们对电台里悲伤音乐的反应，或许与弦乐四重奏的忧郁旋律或歌手的伤感唱腔无关，而是源于我们体内发生的一种自然化学反应。
Maybe that explanation is music to your ears if you're wondering why you’ve been listening to Adele on repeat!
如果你正疑惑自己为什么会反复循环阿黛尔的歌曲，这个解释或许会让你豁然开朗！